<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Go ahead, make my day</title><description>Thoughts, stories and ideas.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><generator>Ghost 0.6</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 21:44:16 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>Upon Reflexion</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I haven’t kept a diary since I was a nine-year-old devoted Spice Girls fan/football geek (thanks Mel C for making those two things compatible). So why start now? Considering what is to come, it seems right; I need to be conscious and aware of my own development and&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/2015/08/18/upon-refelxion/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">7f8fb4fa-6989-4403-83bd-1b99be834381</guid><dc:creator>Sarah Kristine Pedersen</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 21:38:40 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I haven’t kept a diary since I was a nine-year-old devoted Spice Girls fan/football geek (thanks Mel C for making those two things compatible). So why start now? Considering what is to come, it seems right; I need to be conscious and aware of my own development and remind myself about that. Just to be clear, I’m not going to take you through Makers Academy day for day describing every single step of the journey — that I’ll keep to my self and there exist plenty of other Makers blogs dedicated to this. So what is the purpose?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Makers Academy is at this stage all about unknown unknowns. However, what I do know is that I’m going to face some serious challenges on my 16 weeks long journey. I expect to be frustrated every single day about to give up and the only thing keeping me afloat is the expectation that I will be alright — that seems to be the precedence. If you don’t keep spirits high, you are most likely to drag yourself down and fail; keep telling yourself that you’re not good enough and you will end up with a self-fulfilling prophecy. So, that I’m not going to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this journey, I want to follow my progress. Despite evident for your surroundings, progress might not always be evident to yourself. It is easy to feel stuck and lose motivation, but retrospectively, you notice how far you have come. I might not be able to entirely prevent feeling this way, but I am going to do the best I can to accommodate it by evaluating the course and my development day for day, week for week, month for month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I probably wouldn’t have published my thoughts if it wasn’t for the fact that Makers encourage us to write a blog for both ours and their sake. And if I can assist in convincing some of you out there to break free from dragging patterns and revise your future — whether it will take you the coding way or somewhere else — it will be worth it.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>What He Said ...</title><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Twenty years from now you will be more disappointed by the things you didn’t do than by the ones you did. So throw off the bowlines. Sail away from the safe harbor. Catch the trade winds in your sails. Explore. Dream. Discover.” &lt;em&gt;Mark Twain&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Saturday 8.8.2015&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/2015/08/18/what-he-said/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">4b786f75-0dd0-406b-b0e9-fe830c1a2593</guid><dc:creator>Sarah Kristine Pedersen</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 20:32:54 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Twenty years from now you will be more disappointed by the things you didn’t do than by the ones you did. So throw off the bowlines. Sail away from the safe harbor. Catch the trade winds in your sails. Explore. Dream. Discover.” &lt;em&gt;Mark Twain&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Saturday 8.8.2015&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hate quotes — or more precisely, I hate how quotes are being misused. Honestly, I think quotes often devalue the quality of a text. I dislike how quotes are used as a mean to appear well-considered, reflective and enlightened. I dislike how quotes are used as a leverage for placing yourself on the same footing as the originator of the quote. I dislike how quotes tend to be ripped out of a context, twisted or even attributed the wrong person. So why initiate this post with a quote attributed Mark Twain (an attribution that cannot even be verified)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I admit, quotes can capture the reader’s attention and function as potent carriers of meaning; they can condense and encapsulate the message of a text and yes, sometimes they even have the ability of inspiring the audience. However, the vast majority of times, quotes merely make me judge the writer perceiving him as being ignorant (I know, I know, that might say more about me as a person than the writer). I realise this is not the best defence of what is to come. Why? Well, because in my adult life, two quotes in particular have influenced how I think and the decisions I make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first quote, as you might have guessed, is the aforementioned Explore, Dream, Discover — and not just in a travel-sense. Empirically, I know how easy it is to get comfortable and maintain the status quo; educational and job-wise, geographically, and even when it comes to everyday routines. While it might work for years, I find the prospects of always repeating and never challenging myself depressing. That’s why I constantly try to stir up myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m fully aware of the cheesy origin of the second quote; some years ago, I was a keen follower of the TV series “Lost” (well, at least the first three seasons). One of the characters, the enigmatic and strong-willed John Locke, often uttered the words; “Don’t tell me what I can’t do!”. “Don’t tell me what I can’t do”, might seem fairly bland, but it occurred to me how often society in general tells us what to do and discourages us from ambitious, adventurous and anti-conform ideas because they might seem unrealistic or require lots of hard work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve never been resting on my laurels and I believe “that every man is the architect of his own fortune” (oops I did it again), but realising that what you’ve spent years on deciding, studying for, struggling for, and working on is not what you really want to do, is harsh — and I mean really harsh. Even though those years have not been wasted, you can’t help feeling so and I wonder what I could have spent my resources on instead. Some people know from early childhood that they want to become architects, nurses, teachers, football players, actors and so forth; I’ve never felt that way (well, ok, that’s not entirely true; I wanted to become a detective, a damn good detective, and I wanted to be as cool as Tintin). So what happened?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The painfully honest and somewhat boring truth is that I am two years out of university with a masters in Communications (didn’t know what else to study and I figured I had to study something useful and versatile), have years of deeply relevant student job experience and two years of full time job experience — and where has it led me? General marketing jobs in corporate environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, my last job made me question my situation; it’s not that I didn’t like working there (my colleagues were the best!), but managing webinars and writing standard newsletters was not my cup of tea. I started fearing getting stuck in a similar position and for the next many years and continue a career in general marketing that I am not passionate about. I have never chosen the beaten path, and I knew that it was time to do something about my future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some months prior to that, the idea of applying for coding bootcamps had been suggested to me and while I thought of the idea as being “cool” and “bad-ass”, I didn’t take it seriously. Why? I’ve never been a math-prodigy, I have no coding experience whatsoever, I don’t have an understanding of computer science, and it seems like programmers have been dedicated to coding since they were kids. How would I be able to compete with that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For years I’ve wanted to enter the start-up scene but without any extraordinary digital marketing or tech skills, it proved difficult. After my “epiphany”, I spared the idea another thought and I began researching coding bootcamps in London. Then, I came across Makers Academy and that became the beginning of a journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent a long time scrutinising Makers’ reputation to verify their legitimacy. I read blogs and fora, researched partner companies, talked to people in the tech environment and attended Silicon Milkroundabout. All very positive and encouraging. So, even though the idea of learning to code in 16 weeks and gaining enough skills to become a junior developer seemed unbelievable to me, I was convinced. Now was the right time, I quit my job and threw off the bowlines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make a long story short (shorter), I applied, studied, went to the interview, got accepted and now I am on the first week of the pre-course (four weeks of remote studies). Having prepared (both mentally, physically and study-wise) for a long time now, I’m confident that I’m going to make it. The road will be short, steep, sweaty and scary, but I didn’t expect anything else. By the end of the day, applying for this course is a huge leap of faith, and frankly it sounds harder than anything I’ve done before. However, if you never challenge yourself you don’t discover what you are capable of and able to accomplish. Push yourself hard, then harder and even harder than that, and don’t listen to people trying to drag you down just because they are not courageous enough or don’t have what it takes. Trust yourself and jump.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Welcome to Ghost</title><description>&lt;p&gt;You're live! Nice. We've put together a little post to introduce you to the Ghost editor and get you started. You can manage your content by signing in to the admin area at &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;your blog URL&amp;gt;/ghost/&lt;/code&gt;. When you arrive, you can select this post from a list&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/2015/08/16/welcome-to-ghost/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">7ff7c272-a14a-4d8f-a6b7-1c512fdd8ca7</guid><category>Getting Started</category><dc:creator>Sarah Kristine Pedersen</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2015 15:30:27 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;You're live! Nice. We've put together a little post to introduce you to the Ghost editor and get you started. You can manage your content by signing in to the admin area at &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;your blog URL&amp;gt;/ghost/&lt;/code&gt;. When you arrive, you can select this post from a list on the left and see a preview of it on the right. Click the little pencil icon at the top of the preview to edit this post and read the next section!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="gettingstarted"&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ghost uses something called Markdown for writing. Essentially, it's a shorthand way to manage your post formatting as you write!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing in Markdown is really easy. In the left hand panel of Ghost, you simply write as you normally would. Where appropriate, you can use &lt;em&gt;shortcuts&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;style&lt;/strong&gt; your content. For example, a list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Item number one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Item number two
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A nested item&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A final item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or with numbers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember to buy some milk  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drink the milk  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tweet that I remembered to buy the milk, and drank it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id="links"&gt;Links&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to link to a source? No problem. If you paste in a URL, like &lt;a href="http://ghost.org"&gt;http://ghost.org&lt;/a&gt; - it'll automatically be linked up. But if you want to customise your anchor text, you can do that too! Here's a link to &lt;a href="http://ghost.org"&gt;the Ghost website&lt;/a&gt;. Neat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="whataboutimages"&gt;What about Images?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Images work too! Already know the URL of the image you want to include in your article? Simply paste it in like this to make it show up:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ghost.org/images/ghost.png" alt="The Ghost Logo"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not sure which image you want to use yet? That's ok too. Leave yourself a descriptive placeholder and keep writing. Come back later and drag and drop the image in to upload:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="quoting"&gt;Quoting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes a link isn't enough, you want to quote someone on what they've said. Perhaps you've started using a new blogging platform and feel the sudden urge to share their slogan? A quote might be just the way to do it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Ghost - Just a blogging platform&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id="workingwithcode"&gt;Working with Code&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got a streak of geek? We've got you covered there, too. You can write inline &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; blocks really easily with back ticks. Want to show off something more comprehensive? 4 spaces of indentation gets you there. &lt;br&gt;
    .awesome-thing {
        display: block;
        width: 100%;
    }&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="readyforabreak"&gt;Ready for a Break?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throw 3 or more dashes down on any new line and you've got yourself a fancy new divider. Aw yeah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3 id="advancedusage"&gt;Advanced Usage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's one fantastic secret about Markdown. If you want, you can write plain old HTML and it'll still work! Very flexible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;input type="text" placeholder="I'm an input field!"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That should be enough to get you started. Have fun - and let us know what you think :)&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>